

Muhammad Fawad

Software Engineer











Educational Background

- UET Lahore
 BS Computer Science
 2020-2024
- Punjab Group of Colleges
 F.sc Pre Engineering
 2018-2020

Skills

- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- · React.js
- Bootstrap
- PHP
- C/C++
- Python (Pandas, Numpy, Matplot. lib)
- WordPress
- Firebase / SQL
- Responsive Design
- Problem-Solving
- Communication Skills

Professional Experience

TIERS Limited | Internship (MERN)

June 2023 - Present

 Gaining hands-on experience in MERN stack and frontend development.

Interns Pakistan | Internship (Front-End) May 2023 - June 2023

 Working on the client side, I learned HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, and Bootstrap.

Fiverr | React.js & WordPress Developer Sep 2020 - Present

WordPress and React.js expert.
 50+ successful Fiverr projects.
 Established reputation as a Level-1 seller.

About Me

I'm a Lahore-based web developer and freelancer, creating visually appealing websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and frameworks. With a proven track record of successful projects, I'm a fast learner, adaptable to new technologies.

Certifications

- Front-End Website Development (Udemy)
- WordPress Website Developer (Udemy)
- Intro to Data Science (SimpliLearn)

Projects

Tour Planning Agency (using React.js & Firebase)

 Individuals and groups can explore, book tours, and make online payments. The admin has efficient management capabilities for client messages, feedback, and adding new tours to the platform.

Book Reading App (using Flutter & Firebase)

• In the book reading app, users can register, add books to their reading list, continue reading across devices, and utilize a text-to-speech option.

Bus Terminal System (using BST, Stack & Queue)

 CLI-based bus terminal system allows users to view bus timings, reserve seats and enables the admin to schedule buses and issue tickets to customers.

BINGO Game (using α-β pruning & Tkinter UI)

 Python Tkinter-based Bingo game enables users to play against an unbeatable computer opponent.
 The game supports various board sizes.

Mini Social Media (using CLI)

 CLI-based mini social media platform enables users to connect, add friends, create posts, comment, and message each other.

Findeo Group (Using WordPress & Elementor Pro)

 A website that offers expert guidance and support for businesses and individuals across various commercial, industrial, and technological stages.

Creative Crib 7 (Using WordPress & Elementor Pro)

 A global remote team of lead generation specialists, leveraging cloud technology for rapid business growth.